Guide to the Horace Davis Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- University papers, 1901-1916
  - Budget, January 1908 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Carbon from Crothers to Lathrop, 26-Dec-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 27-Dec-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Eells, 27-Dec-07
    - Estimate of Expenditures for year ending, July 31, 1909
    - Memoranda on Budget for January 1908, 3 pg. holograph.
    - Budget Matters Memorandum, 6 pg. holograph
  - By-Laws and Amendments Relating to Business Matters (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Copies of reports of organization committe, by-laws and rules of order, 1st report and 2nd report of Trustee Sloss., 26 Mar 1904-4 Jan 1907
    - Trustee Sloss's report on the organization of financial management of Stanford U., 20-Feb-05
    - TLS from Crothers, 18-Jul-06
    - Proposed revised by-laws of Board of Trustees and amendments to by-laws, 25-Jan-07
    - Carbon from Lathrop to Sloss, 19-Feb-07
  - By-Laws - Rules of Order - Board of Trustees (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Holograph pg. listing President's duties
    - Holograph pg. listing appointment of Subordinate Employees of the Museum and Church
    - Memorandum of suggestions concerning University organization
    - Carbon from Davis to Jordan, 14-Dec-03
    - TLS from S.F. Leib, 16-Dec-03
    - TLS and holograph notes from Crothers, 16-Jun-08
    - By-laws and rules of order of the Board of Trustees, 26 March 1904
  - Campus Residences (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Carbon from E.D. Adams to Lathrop, 22-Jun-06
    - Carbon from Lathrop to Adams, 27-Jun-06
    - Carbon from Crothers to Rep. Eta Deuteron Alumni Ass'n of Theta Delta Chi, 1-Mar-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Lathrop with list of applicants for lots on tract between Lasuen Street and Lagunita, 15-Mar-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Messrs. Wilson and Wilson, 21-Mar-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Lathrop, 3-Apr-07
    - TLS from Crothers, 4-Apr-07; (2 letters)
    - TLS from Dwight M. Davis, 14-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Ruth H. Gilbert to Crothers, 15-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Ruth H. Gilbert, 15-Apr-07
    - Carbon of Petition to Board of Trustees from the Stanford Chapter of Phi Kappa Psi Fraternity, 15-Apr-07
    - TLS from Lathrop, 16-Apr-07
    - TLS from Crothers, 16-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Helen Thoburn, 18-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Dwight M. Davis, 18-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Helen Thoburn, 19-Apr-07
    - Carbon from W.F. Durand to Jordan, 20-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 21-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 23-Apr-07
    - TLS from Wilson and Wilson to Crother[s], 4-May-07
    - TLS from Crothers, 7-May-07
    - TLS from Crothers, 15-May-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Eells, 6-Jun-07
    - Carbon from Eells to Crothers, 7-Jun-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Eells, 8-Jun-07
    - TLS from Crothers, 12-Jul-07
    - TLS from Crothers to Lathrop, 12-Jul-07
    - Copy of In re erection of Residences upon the University Campus
    - Report to the Trustees from Eells, Branner and Lathrop re: Housing of Faculty
  - College Fees (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Extract from Reports of Supreme Court of Wisconsin: In re charging an incidential fee
    - Report of Trustees Davis and Hopkins as Special Committee on laboratory fees, 26-Jan-06
    - TLS from Jordan, 25-May-06
    - TLS from Crothers, 18-Jul-06
    - TL from Crothers to Timothy Hopkins, 9-Jan-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to James N. Gillett, 27-Feb-07
    - Carbon from Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 16-Mar-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 19-Mar-07
    - TLS from Crothers, 28-Mar-07
    - TL from Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 4-Nov-07
    - TL from Crothers to Jordan, 5-Nov-07
    - TL from Crothers to T. Hopkins with memorandum of secretary in re tuition fees charged in law schools, 27-Nov-07
    - TL from Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 8-Jan-08
    - TL from Frederic C. Woodward to Jordan, 8-Jan-08
    - TL from Crothers to Jordan, 9-Mar-08
  - Commission Repairs Power Plant; Museum Restoration (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - TLS from C.D. Marx, 28-Oct-07
    - TL from [Davis] to Marx, 1-Nov-07
    - TLS from Marx, 2-Nov-07
    - TL from M.A. Edwards, 6-Nov-07
    - TLS from Marx, 6-Nov-07
    - TLS from Crothers, 8-Nov-07
    - TLS from Leon Sloss, 8-Nov-07
    - TL from Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 14-Jan-08
    - TL from Crothers to Jordan, 16-Jan-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Marx, 12-Feb-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to H.C. Peterson, 12-Feb-08
    - TLS from Harry C. Peterson, 14-Feb-08
    - TL from Marx to Crothers, 29-Feb-08
    - TLS from Crothers to T. Hopkins, 5-Jun-08
    - Report to the Board of Trustees from the Commission of Engineers of Stanford U. (Marx, Durand and C.B. Wing) with list of accounts, statement of money paid for labor and summary of estimated costs., 26-Jun-08
    - Excerpt from minutes of the Board of Trustees meeting, re the commission of profs. appointed to conduct earthquake damage rebuilding, 29 June 1906
    - ALS from A. Barthalet to [Henry C.] Peterson, 22-Jul-08
    - TL from [H.C. Peterson] to Crothers, 29-Jul-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Peterson with holograph note from Crothers to Davis enclosed, 30-Jul-08
  - Encina hall (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Carbon from Robt. Slattery to P.Q. Atkinson, 28-Sep-05
    - Carbon from Atkinson to Crothers, 30-Sep-05
    - TLS from Jordan, 30-Sep-05
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 30-Sep-05
    - TLS from Crothers, 10-Oct-05
    - TLS from Jordan, 31-Jan-06
    - Carbon from Norris P. Bryan to Lathrop, 3-Feb-06
    - Clippings re Encina Hall discipline problems
    - Carbon from Lathrop to R.D. Fleming, 6-Feb-06
    - TLS from Jordan, 7-Feb-06
    - Carbon from Lathrop to Jordan, 9-Feb-06
    - TLS from Crothers, 16-Feb-06
    - Carbon from Lathrop to Branner, 31-Mar-06
  - Entrance Requirements (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - TLS from Crothers with memo for Suggested Division of the U. Faculty into Divisions and Depts., 9-Aug-04
    - Carbon from the Sec. of the Advisory Board to Jordan re: Combination of Departments, 29-Sep-04
    - Carbon from Crothers to Branner, 19-Jun-08
    - TL from Crothers, 7-Aug-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 3-Sep-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to T. Hopkins, 14-Sep-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Hopkins, 16-Sep-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Stillman, 16-Sep-08
    - ALS from Crothers with list of entrance requirements from other universities and colleges, 24-Oct-08
    - Statement adopted by Academic Council, re action of faculty re Hygenics and Drawing, 10 Jan 1908
    - Statement adopted by Academic Council, with page on Limited Election in Entrance Requirements and Undergraduate Work, 9 Jan 1909
    - Listing of Entrance Requirements for Stanford U. and 58 other universities and colleges, both State and private
  - Finance (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Amts. due on building contracts, 30-Oct-03
    - TLS from Crothers to Lathrop Report on Functions of the Finance Committee, 3-Dec-03
    - Estimated Annual Income and Expenditures of Stanford U. from June 1, 1903 to June 1, 1904 and approximate totals to be paid on Buildings, 1-Jun-04
    - List of expense from Chas. Ed. Hodges, Architect's Office, 15-Jul-04
    - Statement of appropriations, 1906-1907
    - TL from Crothers with Report of Insurance in Force, 23-Feb-07
    - List of appropriations in force, 28-Mar-07
    - Treasurer's statement, 30 May 1907-25 Jun 1907
    - Statement of Incomes and Expenditures, 31-May-07
    - Carbon from Frank Miller to T. Hopkins, 15-Mar-09
  - Insurance (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - TLS from Alfred Stillman, 15-May-08
    - Fire protection and equipment report, 20-May-08
    - Carbon from W.S. Duval, 27-May-08
    - List of Property at Stanford U. and Palo Alto Farm and Vina and Gridley Ranches destructible by Fire; approximate estimate of cost for extending fire protection to outer quad buildings; possible loss to U. buildings and contents, 28-May-08
    - Carbon from Commission of Engineers of Stanford U. to the Board of Trustees, 29-May-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Alfred Stillman, 20-Oct-08
    - Carbon from Duval to Crothers, 21-Oct-08
    - TLS from Crothers to Duval, 23-Oct-08
    - Carbon from Duval to Crothers with list of insurance rates, 27-Oct-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Mrs. P.L. Crovat, 4-Nov-08
  - Junior College (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - 2 carbons from A.T. Murray to Jordan and from Jordan to the Board of Trustees (respectively) with report of Advisory Board on the Junior College Plan, adopted 7 May 1908, 7 and 9 May 1908
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 12-May-08
    - Carbon from Jordan to Crothers, 13-May-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 14-May-08
    - Carbon from Jordan to Eells, 17-Feb-09
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 21-Apr-09
    - Report on Possible Reorganization of Stanford U. on the Harvard Plan
  - Library (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - TLS from T. Hopkins with library estimate for 1909 - 1910, in detail, 28-Jan-09
    - TLS from Jordan with statements from executive heads re methods of apportioning the the amount of funds alloted to their depts. for purchase of books, 19-Apr-09
    - TLS from George T. Clark, 29-Apr-09
  - McCulloch's Attach on Lathrop (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - TLS from Jordan with clipping on the affair, 20-Apr-06
  - President's Reports - University Publications (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - TLS from Crothers, 12-Dec-06
    - TLS from Crothers, 2-Apr-07
    - TL from [Davis] to Jordan, 3-Apr-07
    - TLS from [G.A.] Clark, 5-Apr-07
    - TL from Lathrop, 12-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Lathrop, 16-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Jordan to Crothers, 17-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 18-Apr-07
    - TLS from Jordan, 19-Apr-07
    - TLS from Crothers, 25-Apr-07
  - Railroad on Campus (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Carbon from O.L. Elliott to Crothers, 23-Nov-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Elliott, 25-Nov-07
    - TL from Elliott to L.E. Hanchett, 2-Dec-07
    - TL from Hanchett to Elliott, 4-Dec-07
    - Carbon from R.L. Wilbur and J.E. McDowell to the Board of Trustees, 21-Jan-08
    - TL from Crothers to Wilbur, 24-Jan-08
    - Carbon from Elliott to Hanchett, 27-Jan-08
    - Carbon from Hanchett to Elliott, 31-Jan-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Wilbur, 10-Feb-08
    - Carbon no sig. to Board of Truste, 25-Feb-08
  - Reports (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Report of the Committee upon Auditing, Organization and Rules, Part I -, 31-Oct-03
    - Organization, By-Laws and Rules of The Board of Trustees of The Leland Stanford Junior Universit
    - Amendments in Report of the Committee Upon Auditing, Organization and Rules
    - 1st Report - Organization of Board
    - Organization of the Faculty of Stanford U.
    - TLS from Crothers to Members of the Committee upon Organization with report of the Organization Committee upon the Organization of the Faculty, 29-Apr-04
    - Short statement on requisitions
  - Retirement of Professors - Carnegie Pension Fund (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Carbon from Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 12-Sep-06
    - Carbon from Fernando Sanford to Jordan, 12-Sep-06
    - TLS from Crothers, 25-Sep-06
    - TLS from Crothers to Jordan, 10-Oct-06
    - TLS from Jordan to Crothers, 12-Oct-06
  - Salary Matters and Promotions (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Two Salary Rolls, 1903-1904
    - List of faculty resignations and appointments, degrees conferred by depts. and list of small or weak depts., 1-Aug-04
    - Report from Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 15-Nov-04
    - Tentative Salary Roll with Roll for 1904 - 1905, 1905-1906
    - Final Salary Roll, 1905-1906
    - List of Faculty with provisional list of salaries and notes for benefit of U. Committee, 1905-1907
    - Carbon from Jordan to Crothers with tentative pay roll for 1905 - 1906, 7-Feb-05
    - TLS from Jordan, 4-Nov-05
    - TLS from Jordan, 12-Dec-05
    - ALS from Crothers, 16-Dec-05
    - TL from President [Jordan] to the University Committee of the Board of Trustees, 19-Dec-05
    - Holograph memorandum of salaries as adopted May 1905
    - Salary Roll, 1906-1907
    - Actual Salary Roll, Departmental, 1906-1907
    - Departmental summary, salaries and increases, 1906-1907, 1907-1908
    - TLS from Jordan, 25-Jan-06
    - TLS from Jordan, 27-Jan-06
    - TLS from Jordan, 30-Jan-06
    - TL from George Hempl to Jordan, 3-Feb-06
    - Holograph list of names suggested by Prof. Howison, 3-Feb-06
    - 2 TLS from Jordan, 5-Feb-06
    - ALS from G.H. Howison, 8-Feb-06
    - TLS from Jordan, 10-Feb-06
    - 2 TLS from Jordan, 12-Feb-06
    - TLS from E.D. Adams to Jordan, 13-Feb-06
    - TLS from Jordan, 13-Feb-06
    - TL from an Associate Prof. of Education to Jordan with statement on salaries, 14-Feb-06
    - TLS from Crothers, 15-Feb-06
    - TLS from L.M. Hoskins to Jordan, 15-Feb-06
    - TLS from Jordan with attached copies of Hempl Correspondence (4 items), all carbons, all 1906, 16-Feb-06
    - TLS from Lathrop, 19-Feb-06
    - TLS from Jordan, 19-Feb-06
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan with Salary Roll of Pres. and Faculty and list of appointments, 24-Feb-06
    - Tentative Salary Roll for 1906 - 1907 with holograph notes and summary of salaries by position, 17-Jul-06
    - TLS from Lathrop, 4-Sep-06
    - Holograph note from [Davis] to [Crothers] with tentative salary roll for 1906 - 1907 and holograph notes, 4-Sep-06
    - TLS from Crothers, 5-Sep-06
    - Carbon from Crothers to Lathrop with salary memoranda, 6-Sep-06
    - TLS from Crothers, 26-Sep-06
    - TLS from Jordan, 9-Oct-06
    - Salary Roll by Departments, 1907-1908
    - Tentative Salary Roll, 1907-1908
    - TLS from Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 23-Jan-07
    - Carbon from Lathrop to Jordan, 25-Jan-07
    - Carbon from Jordan to Lathrop, 29-Jan-07
    - TL from Crothers to Jordan, 31-Jan-07
    - 2 carbons from Lathrop to Jordan, 7-Feb-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 1-Mar-07
    - Salary Roll, 22-Mar-07
    - Resolutions of Trustees relative to salaries, 29 Mar-25 Oct 1907
    - TLS from Crothers, 1-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 2-Apr-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Branner, 4-Apr-07
    - Comparison of salaries (in a folder):, 10-Apr-07
      - Carbon from Crothers to Walter Williams, 10-Apr-07
      - TLS from Crothers, 10-Apr-07
      - Holograph pgs. of statistics on Berkeley and Stanford salaries compared
      - Comparison of Stanford and Berkeley salaries
      - Comparison of salaries of instruction only at Stanford and Berkeley
      - Comparison of Stanford and Berkeley salary rolls, 1901 - 1902
    - Carbon from Crothers to Eells, 16-Apr-07
    - TLS from Crothers, 18-Apr-07
    - Salary Roll, 1908-1909
    - TLS from Crothers to Stanton Griffis, 18-Jan-08
    - TLS from Jordan, 11-Feb-08
    - Tentative Salary Roll by rank, 1909-1910
    - TLS from Eells, 6-Feb-09
  - University Committee - Miscellaneous Matters (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Memorandum for Organization Committee, extracts of minutes of Board meeting of this date with special regulations governing admission of women, 22 Feb and 29 Mar 1905
    - Carbon from Jordan to Lathrop, 13-Feb-06
    - Carbon from Lathrop to Jordan, 15-Feb-06
    - Carbon from Crothers, 15-Feb-06
  - Various Matters (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Quote from Jordan
    - TLS from Jordan, 21-Jan-01
    - TLS from Jordan, 24-Jan-01
    - TLS from George B. Cartelyou, 26-Mar-01
    - TLS from Clifford [H.] Moore, 29-Apr-02
    - TLS from Jordan, 15-May-02
    - TLS from Jordan with copy of letter [22 Apr. 1902] from [Jordan] to [Prof. Pease], 16-May-02
    - TLS from S.F. Leib, 16-May-02
    - TLS from Jordan, 21-May-02
    - TLS from S.F. Leib, 21-May-02
    - TLS from Jordan, 24-May-02
    - TLS from S.F. Leib, 31-May-02
    - TLS from Jordan, 31-May-02
    - TLS from Jordan, 9-Jun-02
    - TLS from Jordan, 23-Sep-02
    - Holograph note requesting Davis to attend a Board of Trustees meeting, 3 Oct. 1902., 1902, Sep-Oct
    - TLS from Jordan, 24-Oct-02
    - ALS from Crothers with clipping re a Bill to Determine Validity of S.U. Trusts and Their Amendments; pamphlet Assembly Bill, introduced by Mr. Wright re same; and cvr., 20-Jan-03
    - TLS from Jordan, 2-Feb-03
    - TLS from Max Farrand, 7-Mar-03
    - TLS from Jordan, 18-Apr-03
    - TLS from S.F. Leib, 7-May-03
    - AL from [Davis] to Mrs. Stanford, 11-May-03
    - TLS from Crothers to [Davis], 2-Jul-03
    - TLS from Crothers, 17-Jul-03
    - TLS from S.F. Leib, 12-Aug-03
    - TLS from S.F. Leib to Jordan, 12-Aug-03
    - TLS from Jordan, 4-Sep-03
    - TLS from Jordan, 9-Sep-03
    - TLS from Jordan, 11-Sep-03
    - TLS from S.F. Leib, 8-Oct-03
    - TLS from Leib, 11-Nov-03
    - TLS from Leib, 13-Nov-03
    - TLS from Crothers to Leib, 3-Dec-03
    - TLS from Jordan, 9-Dec-03
    - Ptd. invitation from Union League Club to attend Ladies Night with holograph note on back, 16-Dec-03
    - TLS from O.L. Elliott, 23-Dec-03
    - ALS from Jordan, 4-Jan-04
    - ALS from J.M. Stillman, 15-Feb-04
    - ALS from Stillman, 18-Feb-04
    - Carbon to Jordan from O. L. Elliott. Diplomas, 9-Apr-04
    - LS from Jordan re wording of diplomas, 11-Apr-04
    - TLS from Jordan with ptd. commencement calendar for the U. of Calif, 13 - 21 May 1904, 9-May-04
    - ALS from Wm. H. Baldwin, 15-Mar-06
    - ALS from C.A. Duniway, 2-Jun-06
    - ALS from Chester Rowell, 30-Jun-06
    - TLS from George C. Pardee, 5-Jul-06
    - TLS from Farrand, 22-Sep-06
    - TLS from Pardee, 14-Dec-06
    - ALS from Benj[amin] I. Wheeler, 26-Dec-06
    - TLS from [Robert M. O'Reilly], 11-Feb-07
    - Carbon from Lathrop to T. Hopkins, 18-Mar-07
    - Carbon from Lathrop to Hopkins, 21-Mar-07
    - Carbon from Lathrop to Louis M. Orchard, 4-Jun-07
    - Carbon from Crothers, 2-Oct-07
    - Carbon from Chas. D. Marx to the Board of Trustees, 30-Jul-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to J.E. Lewi, 12-Nov-08
    - ALS from Booker T. Washington, 7-Feb-13
    - ALS from Booker T. Washington, 28-Oct-14
  - Wine Agency, 1907 - 1908 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - ALS/TLS from W.W. Stone to Lathro with ALS dated 10 Aug. [18]97 from Chas. A. Murdock to Davis, 15-Jan-07
    - Carbon from Louis M. Orchard to Lathrop, 15-May-07
    - TLS from P.C. Rossi, 9-Jan-08
    - Carbon from S.M. Mandel to the Finance Committee of the Board of Trustees, 14-Jan-08
    - TLS from Lathrop, 17-Jan-08
    - TLS from Lathrop, 18-Jan-08
    - TLS from Leib, 20-Jan-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Leib, 15-Jun-08
    - Holograph card (very small)
  - Powers of the President re. removal of faculty member. Copies of letters from Jordan to members of the Board. Also drafts of letters, (holograph, in Jordan's hand), 1906 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Misellaneous Pamphlets and Addresses (not in a folder)
    - Chinese Immigration. Speech given by Davis in the House of Representatives, 8 Jun 1878
    - Meaning of the University. Address by Davis on Founder's Day, 9 Mar 1894
    - 2 addresses by Mrs. Jane L. Stanford to the Board of Trustees, 31 May 1899 and 3 Oct 1902
    - Board of Trustees - Report of Organization Committee upon Organization of the Faculty and Articles of Organization of the Faculty of the U., 31-Mar-04
    - General Legislation and Standing Regulations of the Faculty, Aug-07
    - Some Radical Needs at Stanford. Reprinted from Sequoia and Alumnus, (respectively). Written by Davis., March and May 1908
    - Vocational Training. Phi Beta Kappa address at Stanford given by Davis, 18-May-09
    - An Afternoon View of College Life. Address by Davis for Founder's Day, 9-Mar-12
    - Dr. Benjamin Gott - A Family of Doctors. By Davis, reprinted from The Publications of The Colonial Society of Mass., Vol. XII, 1909
    - The Oregon Trail. By Davis, 1910
    - Williams College in 1845. By Davis, 29-Sep-11
    - Memorial Resolution of the Chit-Chat Club for Davis, 14-Aug-16
    - Memorial Tribute to Davis from the Board of Trustees of the Calif. School of Mechanical Arts.
    - Bound book of notes of comparative readings made by Davis. Volume presented by him to the Stanford Library just prior to his death.
    - Memorial resolution from Stanford University Board of Trustees
- Personal papers
  - "Old Times," manuscript by Davis read to the Chit-Chat Club, 8-Mar-15 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous scrapbooks, albums, papers (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 1. Date book Entertainments, 1 Jan 1908-13 May 1909
    - 2. ALS to Davis from Your brother Andrew, 4 Aug 1859
    - 3. Calif. State and County License for selling goods: granted to Davis, 10 Sep 1857
    - 4. Letter to General Conference of the Unitarian Church. (Davis was on the Committee of Conference, 1915
    - 5. Diploma from Harvard University - Bachelor of Arts Degree. Received by Davis, 18 Jun 1849
    - 6. Album with sketches and photographs of Davis early homes.
    - 7. Passport for Davis, signed by James G. Blaine, Dept. of State., 29 Dec 1890
    - 8. Two Standard Diaries containing notes, checks, and clippings and personal mementoes, 1907-1908 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 9. Album containing clippings and letters re Davis' election as President of the State University; also, invitations and letters concerning the inaugeration. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 10. Two ledgers containing misc. information (facts, notes and figures). (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - 11. Ledger of expenses for various companies and organizations. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 12. Ledger of Inventory of Property [San Francisco]. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - 13. Music book belonging to Davis - contains sheet music and the words. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - 14. Album containing various clippins re Stanford (particularly the Goebel case, the rioting of 1908 and the Jordan administration)., circa 1906 1908 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - 15. Articles by Davis in The Overland Monthly: Collegiate Education of Women, The Loss of the Harriet, and The Nicaragua Canal, Oct 1890; Aug 1891; Mar 1892 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - 16. Articles by Davis in The Atlantic Monthly: Shakespeare and Copyright, and in Poet-Lore: Shakespeare and Lyly, Feb 1893; Apr 1893 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Davis' Publications (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - 1. California Breadstuffs -- reprinted from the Journal of Political Economy, # 2.
    - 2. Christianity in Japan -- reprinted from the Unitarian Review.
    - 3. The Flouring Industry of California -- reprinted from The Overland Monthly, Jun 1897
    - 4. Mrs. Lucretia (Chandler) Bancroft: A letter to her daughter, Mrs. Gheradi. With intro duction by Horace Davis, 1901
    - 5. The Public Ministry of Jesus, 1911
    - 6. [Not by Davis] The Union Society of the Civil War with its constitution, etc. and a list of members, Davis included
      (See also loose items in box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Papers
    - Manuscript, Is Christianity Applicable to Everyday Life?, 1-Feb-14 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - The controversy over William C. Hinckley's will, 1880-1899 (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - Court Summons, 1899
      - Last Will and Testament of William C. Hinckley
      - By-Laws of the Board of Trustess of the Wm. and Alice Hinckley Fund
      - Superior Court Summons, Apr 6, 1881